Guide to the Lantern Slide Collection c. 1860-1942 PR 70
New-York Historical Society
- Series II: Songs, 2
  - That Dreamy Italian Waltz (1) (Box 91, Item PR-070-0002-0099)
  - That Hypnotizing Man (1) (Box 92, Item PR-070-0002-0100)
    lampshades, fans, pillows, girls
  - That Ragtime Goblin (Man/Rag?) (2) (Box 92, Item PR-070-0002-0101)
    moons, guitars, goblins, ears, couples, walls, nets, waterfalls
  - That Sorry D.? (1) (Box 92, Item PR-070-0002-0102)
    engagement rings, currents, rivers
  - Tie That Binds, The (1) (Box 92, Item PR-070-0002-0103)
    cities, lights, apartment buildings, buses, people
  - Tis Not Always Bullets That Kill (3) (Box 92, Item PR-070-0002-0104)
    Stereopticon and Film Exchange, 108 Franklin Street, Chicago, Illinois: George W. Bond, Chicago, Illinois: c1901
    flags, canes, rocks, men, houses, moons, flowers, lakes, trees, couples
  - Undertaker Man, The (3) (Box 92, Item PR-070-0002-0105)
    bread, candies, flowers, suitors, girls, boys, luggage, chef, bell boys, staircase, house interiors
  - Valley Flower (1) (Box 92, Item PR-070-0002-0106)
    bears, Indians
  - Volunteer Organist, The (9) (Box 92, Item PR-070-0002-0107)
    T. Foster, 140 Erie Street, J. C.
    text, pipe organs, churches, audience, homeless men
  - When I Long for You (1) (Box 92, Item PR-070-0002-0108)
    flowers, girls, vases
  - When Teddy comes marching home (1) (Box 92, Item PR-070-0002-0109)
    Scott and Van Altena, 59 Pearl Street, New York; 10 Buffalo Slide Exchange
    hawks, hearts
  - When the Tide is Turning (3) (Box 92, Item PR-070-0002-0110)
    Scott and Van Altena, 59 Pearl Street, New York (Set 1)
    wood, forest, couples, oceans, waves, canes, beaches, butterflies, fans
  - When the Whippoorwill Sings Marguerite (13) (Box 92, Item PR-070-0002-0111)
    dogs, girls, steps, bridges, houses, fences, house interiors, fathers, boys, flags, lamps, lakes, sunsets, moons, oceans, windows, parasols, tunnels, birds, nest, text
  - When You Kiss an Italian Girl (1) (Box 92, Item PR-070-0002-0112)
    pasta, girls, hands
  - When You Were Sweet Sixteen (1) (Box 92, Item PR-070-0002-0113)
    J. D. Cress: c1900
    seas, clouds, sunsets
  - When You're Lonesome (2) (Box 92, Item PR-070-0002-0114)
    Scott and Van Altena, 59 Pearl Street, New York; 12 Buffalo Slide Exchange
    couples, performances, stage, masks, beaches, oceans, seats
  - Why Don't You Try (a.k.a. The Rolling Chair Song) (19) (Box 92, 93, Item PR-070-0002-0115)
    DeWitt C. Wheeler, 1215 Broadway, Daly's Theatre Building, New York: c1905
    text, wheeled chairs, Afro-Americans, couples, boardwalks, beaches, oceans, sunsets, houses, swings, toys, stores, balconies, horses,
  - Winter Time (13) (Box 93, Item PR-070-0002-0116)
    DeWitt C. Wheeler, Inc., 120-122 West 31st Street, New York (Set 1); Levi Company, Inc., 1560 Broadway, New York (Set 3)
    text, snow, sleighs, horses, couples, trees, ponds, moons, ice skaters, house interiors
  - With the girl of my leave (1) (Box 93, Item PR-070-0002-0117)
    Dewitt C. Wheeler, 51 West 28th Street, N.Y.
    girls, rocks, grasses, trees
  - Women of Mumbles Head (9) (Box 93, Item PR-070-0002-0118)
    sailboats, wooden lifevests, shipwrecks, women, men, sailing, ocean, lighthouses
  - You're Just too Sweet to Live (1) (Box 93, Item PR-070-0002-0119)
    forests, paths
  - You've Got the Wrong Number, But You've Got the Right Girl (1) (Box 93, Item PR-070-0002-0120)
    DeWitt C. Wheeler, Inc., 120 West 31st Street, New York
    telephones, couples
  - Zona (3) (Box 93, Item PR-070-0002-0121)
    girls, hats, fans, guitars, grapes
  - Untitled (1) (Box 93, Item PR-070-0002-0122)
    Acme Exchange, 150 East 14th Street, New York
    moons, flowers, shrubs, stars
  - Untitled (10) (Box 93, Item PR-070-0002-0123)
    Acme Exchange, 150 East 14th Street, New York: c1901
    couples, trees, forests, boats, rocks, seas
  - Untitled (1) (Box 93, Item PR-070-0002-0124)
    Acme Exchange, 51 West 28th Street, New York
    stars, bench, path
  - Untitled (4) (Box 94, Item PR-070-0002-0125)
    Chas. Beseler Company, New York
    brides, steps, angels, bridge
  - Untitled (7) (Box 94, Item PR-070-0002-0126)
    Chicago Transparency Company, 84 Adams Street, F. T. McCleod.
    flags, soldiers, couples, benches, steps, weddings, churches, horses, carriages, battlefields
  - Untitled (2) (Box 94, Item PR-070-0002-0127)
    waterfalls, rocks, Afro-Americans, fields
  - Untitled (1) (Box 94, Item PR-070-0002-0128)
    DeWitt C. Wheeler, 51 West 28th Street, N.Y.
    tents, valleys, roads
  - Untitled (2) (Box 94, Item PR-070-0002-0129)
    Harry F. Stains, 713 North 41st Street, Philadelphia, PA
    ships, girls, beaches, oceans
  - Untitled (1) (Box 94, Item PR-070-0002-0130)
    brides
  - Untitled (3) (Box 94, Item PR-070-0002-0131)
    Henry B. Ingram, Room 815, 108 Fulton Street, New York; Colored by Joseph Hawkes
    houses, men, couples, photographs, rocks
  - Untitled (1) (Box 94, Item PR-070-0002-0132)
    Ingram & Wheeler, Makers, 57 West 28th Street, N.Y.
    couples, gardens, gifts, chairs, children
  - Untitled (2) (Box 94, Item PR-070-0002-0133)
    John Walters, Bath Beach, N.Y.
    moon, men, women, couples, houses and homes, flowers, paths
  - Untitled (2) (Box 94, Item PR-070-0002-0134)
    New York Stereopticon Slide Company, 53 West 28th Street, New York
    Afro-Americans, guns, children, parents, couples
  - Untitled (1) (Box 94, Item PR-070-0002-0135)
    farms, women
  - Untitled (3) (Box 94, Item PR-070-0002-0136)
    parties, groups, couples, couches, horses, carriages, street lamps
  - Untitled (2) (Box 94, Item PR-070-0002-0137)
    jewelry boxes, parasols, couples, hearts, walls, canes, clouds
  - Untitled (2) (Box 94, Item PR-070-0002-0138)
    frames, fences, roses, couples, canes, moneybags, girls
  - Untitled (3) (Box 94, Item PR-070-0002-0139)
    ropes, hearts, couples, walls, photographs, frames, lakes
  - Untitled (2) (Box 94, Item PR-070-0002-0140)
    parasols, couples, paths, gardens, lakes, bridges, trees
  - Untitled (2) (Box 94, Item PR-070-0002-0141)
    railroads, couples, clouds, letters, handkerchiefs
  - Untitled (1) (Box 94, Item PR-070-0002-0142-001)
    horses, hay carts, men, working
  - Untitled (1) (Box 94, Item PR-070-0002-0142-002)
    clouds, fences, poinsettia trees, mountains
  - Untitled (1) (Box 94, Item PR-070-0002-0142-003)
    fans, flowers, couples
  - Untitled (1) (Box 94, Item PR-070-0002-0142-004)
    newspapers, men, fireplaces
  - Untitled (1) (Box 94, Item PR-070-0002-0142-005)
    hearts, spider webs, couples
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-006)
    clocks, couples
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-007)
    couples, lakes
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-008)
    rings, crowns, castles, couples
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-009)
    couples, lawns, houses
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-010)
    couples, gardens, paths, benches
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-011)
    hearts, daisies, couples, parasols
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-012)
    frames, dogs, boats, factories, couples
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-013)
    drums, violins, girls
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-014)
    steps, couples
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-015)
    couples
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-016)
    couples, desks
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-017)
    waterfalls, couples, hearts
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-018)
    shops, people, cities
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-019)
    couples, paths, bridges, fields
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-020)
    babies, couples, candles
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-021)
    hearts, houses, moons
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-022)
    couples, children, patterns, flowers
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-023)
    children, churches, couples
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-024)
    couples, canes, paths
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-025)
    rings, butterflies, roses, couples, marriages, brides, grooms
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-026)
    walls, hearts, flowers, couples
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-027)
    house, sunlight, couples
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-028)
    lakes, benches, couples
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-029)
    daisies, girls
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-030)
    benches, couples, covered paths
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-031)
    leaves, roses, couples
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-032)
    butterflies, frames, couples, roses
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-033)
    planes, battleships, oceans, mountains
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-034)
    wedding rings, bells, couples, brides, grooms, weddings
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-035)
    fans, parasols, couples
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-036)
    railroads, railroad stations
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-037)
    fans, couples, arms
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-038)
    frames, couples, priests, marriages, brides, grooms
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-039)
    leaves, women
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0142-040)
    hearts, pillows, flowers
  - Untitled (6) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0143)
    spinning wheels, books, men, creeks, couples, farms, flags, churches, wells, moons
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0143)
    Simpson's Celebrated Slides: A. L. Simpson, New York
    gardens, fields
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0144)
    Stereopticon and Film Exchange: G. W. Bond, Chicago, Illinois: c1903
    farms, cows, women
  - Untitled (2) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0145)
    paths, moons, wood, couples, clouds, trees, men, canes, benches, ponds
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0146-001)
    Afro-Americans, cotton fields
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0146-002)
    fences, houses, men, women
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0146-003)
    trolleys, people, moons
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0146-004)
    beaches, parasols, shells, sunsets, docks
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0146-005)
    brides, boxes, crying, bricks
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0146-006)
    brides, loveseats, staircases, palms
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0146-007)
    couples, frames, flowers, fences
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0146-008)
    women, flowers, wreaths
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0146-009)
    dirigibles, planets, stars, clouds
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0146-010)
    cities, country, horses, carriages, shops, photographs
  - Untitled (1) (Box 95, Item PR-070-0002-0146-011)
    couples, fences, trees, hats
- Series III: Announcements, 3
  Lantern slides used in theaters for announcement and advertising purposes.
  - Auction Sale Daily and Nightly at the Shatruka, 807 Kingsley Street Next-to West End Hotel Turkish Rugs Japanese Art Goods East India Ware. (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0001)
  - C. Bockelmann, First-Class Cash Grocer, Teas, Coffees, Fruit and Vegetables, 758 Gravesend Ave. cor. Ditmars Ave. Tel. 4149 Flatbush/ Heckers Cream Oatmeal Packages 25c (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0002)
  - Do You See the Point? It Is Cooper's Empire Garden. (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0003)
  - Good Night! Good Ice-Cream Day's. (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0004)
  - Hot Night! Day's Must Be Packed. (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0005)
  - New Woven Wire Cots $1.00/ Upholstered Cots #1.00/ Cotton Pads $1.00/ D. Gates 501 Main St./ Goods Taken Back at Half Price (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0006)
  - Place Your Ice Cream order for Sunday at Cooper's Fairy Garden 2nd Ave. (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0007)
  - There is a fine Display of Aluminum Goods at the Old Mill. (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0008)
  - Warm Night! Good Many People Going to Day's (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0009)
  - We Give the Best Value for your Money. Mattison Ave. Jewlery Store. Caswell. (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0010)
  - Will You Go? Day's To Night (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0011)
  - Cooper's Empire Garden See the Words Cooper's Ice Cream. (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0012)
    Dewitt C. Wheeler, 51 West 28th Street, New York
  - "there!" In Peace as in War/ Your Membership does it -- JOIN/ Third Red Cross Roll Call/ Nov. 2-11 (Armistice Day)/ Photographed at the $5,000,000 Brooklyn, Sept. 13, 1919. (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0013)
    Standard Slide Corp., 209 West 48th Street, New York
  - "there!" In Peace as in War/ Your Membership does it -- JOIN/ Third Red Cross Roll Call/ Nov. 2-11 (Armistice Day)/ Photographed at the $5,000,000 Brooklyn, Sept. 13, 1919. (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0014)
  - "there!" In Peace as in War/ Your Membership does it -- JOIN/ Third Red Cross Roll Call/ Nov. 2-11 (Armistice Day)/ Photographed at the $5,000,000 Brooklyn, Sept. 13, 1919. (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0015)
  - Come Again and Bring Your Friends. (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0016)
  - Good Afternoon (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0017)
  - Good Afternoon/ Call Again (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0018)
  - Good Evening/ Hurrah for the Irish! (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0019)
  - Good Night (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0020)
  - Good Night/ Come Again (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0021)
  - This Concludes the Performance. Kindly Pass Out. Many Thanks. Call Again. (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0022)
  - This Concludes the Entire Performance/ All those that came in late may remain to see the next (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0023)
    A. E. Wells, 44 West 28th Street, New York
  - This Concludes this Performance/ Please Call Again/ This Way Out/ This Way Out (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0024)
    Alfred L. Harstn and Co., 138 East 14th Street, New York
  - This Concludes this Performance (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0025)
    Art Sign and Slide Works, 143 East 23rd Street, New York
  - Good Night (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0026)
    Economic Series
  - All Out Please. This concludes the program (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0027)
    Globe Illustrated Bureau, 40 West 28th Street, New York
  - Good Night (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0028)
    Harstn and Co., 138 East 14th Street, New York
  - This Concludes the Entire Performance/ All Out/ Please Call Again (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0029)
  - Good Night (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0030)
    Levi's Perfection Slides, 64 East 14th Street, New York, U. S. A.
  - Good Night (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0031)
    S. Lobin, 21 South 8th Street, Philadelphia, PA, U. S. A.
  - Good Night (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0032)
  - Merry Christmas (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0033)
  - Make Yourself at Home (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0034)
  - Welcome Post No Bills (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0035)
  - Welcome (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0036)
  - Hats Off Please (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0037)
  - Ladies Kindly Remove Your Hats (Box 96, Item PR-070-0003-0038)
  - Interval Five Minutes (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0039)
    B. Kahn Wholesale Opticians, 32 Maiden Lane, New York
  - Intermission One Minute to change Film (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0040)
    Charles A. Gunby, Brooklyn, New York
  - A Short Intermission During Change of Film Don't go out. (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0041)
  - One Minute Please (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0042)
  - No Smoking Here Smoke Elsewhere (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0043)
  - Gentlemen. No Smoking (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0044)
    Kromograf Slide Co., New York -- Premier Anouncement Slides
  - In order to conform to the fire laws, we request the gentlement to check their cigars before entering. (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0045)
  - Kindly Avoid Loud Talking and Profane Language (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0046)
    Chas. A. Calehuff, N. E. Cor. 4th and Green Streets, Philadelphia, PA
  - Don't Be Afraid to Join in the Chorus with Our Singer (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0047)
    German-American Cinematograph and Film Co., -TEL.; Eberhard Schneider, Berlin--New York.
  - Don't forget your Umbrellas (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0048)
  - Entire New Programme To-Morrow (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0049)
  - New Pictures Tomorrow (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0050)
  - If You Like Our Shows Tell Your Friends If Not, Tell Us. (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0051)
    Chas. A. Calehuff, N. E. Cor. 4th and Green Streets, Philadelphia, PA.
  - We Always Have the Best Moving Pictures (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0052)
  - We Reserve the Right to Reject and Objectionable Person. (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0053)
  - Pictures Changed Every Day (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0054)
  - Beasts of the Jungle at this Theatre/ The Biggest and Best Animal Picture Produced/ Solax. (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0055)
    Novelty Slide Co., 20 East 14th Street, New York
  - Beasts of the Jungle at this Theatre/ The Biggest and Best Animal Picture Produced/ Solax. (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0056)
  - Beasts of the Jungle at this Theatre/ The Biggest and Best Animal Picture Produced/ Solax. (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0057)
  - Butterfly Dance (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0058)
  - Devil's Amusement (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0059)
  - Laundry Scene (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0060)
  - N. Y. Fire Dept. comming down Bradway [sic] (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0061)
  - Man in the Moon (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0062)
    T. H. McAllister, New York
  - Children Not Holding Half Coupons Cannot Occupy Seats. Avoid Accidents Don't Stand Your Children on Seats. (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0063)
  - Children Under Sixteen Years of Age Not Admitted Unless Accompanied By Parent or Guardian. (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0064)
  - Ladies Without Escorts Cordially Invited (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0065)
  - Special Attention Given to Ladies' and Children Attending the Afternoon Performance (Box 97, Item PR-070-0003-0066)
- Series IV: Special Formats, 4
  - Subseries IV.1: Steregraph slides
    - District of Columbia-Washington--Library of Congress, interiors (Box 98, Item PR-070-0004-0001)
      Interior views of the Library of Congress building, showing arches, stairs, statues, columns and windows.
    - Series--Fifth Avenue Building (Box 98, Item PR-070-0004-0002)
      Views of the construction of the Fifth Avenue Building at 200 Fifth Ave. (formerly site of Fifth Avenue Hotel), with shots showing Madison Ave. and Madison Sq. Park, 23rd St. and 24th St., pedestrians, aerial views, construction workers, and building mate
  - Subseries IV.2: Magic lantern slides
    - Uncle Tom (Box 99)
    - Assorted (Box 100-103)